Human Rights Watch records: Record Group 4: Africa Watch 7746709
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series 1: Karen Sorensen, 1979-1996
  - Subseries I.2: Country Files, 1979-1995
    - Cameroon
      - Zaire
        - Newspapers, 1992; (2 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 22 to 23)
        - Press Clippings, 1989-1990; (3 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 24 to 26)
        - Press Clippings, 1990-1993; (9 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 1 to 9)
        - Students, 1990 (Box 261, Folder 10)
        - Reports
          - AP, FBIS, Reuters, 1992; (2 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 11 to 12)
          - General, 1992 (Box 261, Folder 13)
        - United States--Government, 1991-1992 (Box 261, Folder 14)
        - Voix des Sans Voix pour les droits de l'homme, 1991-1992 (Box 262, Folder 1)
      - Zambia
        - Amnesty International, 1993 (Box 262, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 262, Folder 3)
        - Press Clippings, 1989-1992; (4 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 4 to 7)
        - Report--Africa Watch, 1993 (Box 262, Folder 8)
        - Reports, 1992-1994; (2 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 9 to 10)
        - South Africa--Kaunda-DeKlerk Meeting, 1989-1990 (Box 262, Folder 11)
      - Zanzibar--Press Clippings, 1990 (Box 262, Folder 12)
      - Zimbabwe
        - Africa Watch--Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 262, Folder 13)
        - Articles and Wires, 1992 (Box 262, Folder 14)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 262, Folder 15)
        - Council of Churches, 1990-1991 (Box 262, Folder 16)
        - Khaminwa Case 2, 1990-1992 (Box 262, Folder 17)
        - List of Contacts, undated (Box 262, Folder 18)
        - Material--Inside Country, 1991 (Box 262, Folder 19)
        - Musasa Project, 1992 (Box 262, Folder 20)
        - Press Clippings, 1990-1992; (3 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 21 to 23)
        - Reports--FBIS, 1992-1993; (2 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 24 to 25)
        - Women, 1992-1993 (Box 262, Folder 26)
- Series 2: Bronwen Manby Files, 1977-1996
  This series represents Ms. Manby's work as a consultant on South Africa from 1992 to the mid-1990s. After moving through various positions during her tenure at HRW/Africa Watch, she resigned as Deputy Director in 2003. In 2003, Ms. Manby became the Director of the Africa Governance Monitoring and Advocacy Project (AfriMAP) at the Open Society Institute in London.
  - Subseries II.1: South Africa Files, 1977-1996
    Subseries 1: South Africa, 1977-1997 The files are arranged alphabetically by subject and include correspondence, manuscripts, memorandums, newspaper clippings, newsletters and research reports. Through these preceding archival materials, the researcher may trace South Africa's internal political developments from its intense repression of the "independent" homelands to its transformation to a democratic state positively engaged with its neighbors.
    - Press Clippings, 1991-1992; (13 Folders) (Box 263, Folder 1 to 13)
    - Press Clippings, 1993-1994 May; (17 Folders) (Box 264, Folder 1 to 17)
    - Press Clippings--Violence, 1990-1992 June; (18 Folders) (Box 265, Folder 1 to 18)
    - Academic Freedom
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 266, Folder 1)
      - Reports--Africa Watch--Drafts, undated (Box 266, Folder 2)
    - Africa Confidential, 1992-1994, 1996 (Box 266, Folder 3)
    - The Africa Fund, 1989-1994 (Box 266, Folder 4)
    - Africa Watch--Publications, 1989-1994 (Box 266, Folder 5)
    - African American Institute, 1990 (Box 266, Folder 6)
    - African National Congress (ANC)
      - General, 1989-1992 (Box 266, Folder 7)
      - Policy--Internal Affairs, 1991-1994 (Box 266, Folder 8)
    - African Topics, 1994 (Box 266, Folder 9)
    - Aid/Famine, 1991-1993 (Box 266, Folder 10)
    - Aids, 1991-1994 (Box 266, Folder 11)
    - Amnesty International, 1988-1994 (Box 266, Folder 12)
    - Anti-Censorship Group, 1989-1993 (Box 266, Folder 13)
    - Arms Trade, 1991-1994 (Box 266, Folder 14)
    - Army, 1992-1994 (Box 266, Folder 15)
    - Articles, 1989-1994 (Box 266, Folder 16)
    - Association of West European Parliamentarians for Action Against Apartheid (AWEPAA), 1989-1990, 1994 (Box 266, Folder 17)
    - Bophuthatswana
      - Braklaagte and Leeuwfontein, 1989-1991 (Box 267, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Governments, 1990-1991 (Box 267, Folder 2)
      - General Memos, 1990, 1992, 1994 (Box 267, Folder 3)
      - Interviews and Statements, 1990-1991 (Box 267, Folder 4)
      - Legislation, 1977 (Box 267, Folder 5)
      - Political Prisoners, 1991 (Box 267, Folder 6)
      - Press Clippings, 1990-1991, 1993-1994, (4 Folders) (Box 267, Folder 7 to 10)
      - Report (Original), 1991 September (Box 267, Folder 11)
    - Buthelezi/Inkatha Freedom Party (IFP)--Central Negotiations, 1992-1994 (Box 267, Folder 12)
    - Center for Adult Education, 1989 (Box 267, Folder 13)
    - Centre for Applied Legal Studies, 1987, 1988 (Box 267, Folder 14)
    - Children, 1991-1993 (Box 267, Folder 15)
    - Church—South African
      - General, 1987-1988, 1992, 1994 (Box 267, Folder 16)
      - No Neutral Ground, 1988-1988 (Box 267, Folder 17)
    - Ciskei
      - Bisho Massacre, 1992 September 7 (Box 268, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1991 (Box 268, Folder 2)
        - Governments, 1991-1992 (Box 268, Folder 3)
      - FBIS and SWB Reports, 1991 (Box 268, Folder 4)
      - General Memos, 1987, 1991 (Box 268, Folder 5)
      - Goozo, Brig. Gen. O.J.--Press Releases, 1990-1991 (Box 268, Folder 6)
      - Interviews and Statements, 1991 (Box 268, Folder 7)
      - Material from Independent Board of Inquiry into Informal Repression (KBIIR) and East Cape News Agencies (ECNA), 1991 (Box 268, Folder 8)
      - Press Clippings, 1989-1994; (6 Folders) (Box 268, Folder 9 to 14)
      - Report--Original, 1991 December (Box 268, Folder 15)
    - Civil Rights League, 1992-1994 (Box 268, Folder 16)
    - Commission of Inquiry Regarding the Prevention of Public Violence and Intimidation--Press Releases, 1991-1992 (Box 268, Folder 17)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1989-1991 (Box 268, Folder 18)
    - Commonwealth Report, 1991-1994 (Box 268, Folder 19)
    - Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU), 1987-1991 (Box 268, Folder 20)
    - Conscription--Whites, 1992-1993 (Box 268, Folder 21)
    - Constitution, 1992-1993 (Box 268, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 268, Folder 23)
    - Corruption, 1992-1993 (Box 268, Folder 24)
    - Death Penalty, 1988-1993 (Box 268, Folder 25)
    - Democracy in Action, 1992-1994 (Box 268, Folder 26)
    - Democratic Party (DP), 1994 (Box 269, Folder 1)
    - Disabled People, undated (Box 269, Folder 2)
    - Economy, 1992-1994 (Box 269, Folder 3)
    - Education
      - Human Rights/Legal, 1991, 1994 (Box 269, Folder 4)
      - SACHED Trust, 1989 (Box 269, Folder 5)
      - Schools, 1991-1993 (Box 269, Folder 6)
      - Universities, 1991-1992 (Box 269, Folder 7)
    - Einstein Institution, 1991-1992 (Box 269, Folder 8)
    - Election Monitoring and Voter Education, 1994 (Box 269, Folder 9)
    - Embassy of South Africa, 1991-1992 (Box 269, Folder 10)
    - Environment, 1992-1994 (Box 269, Folder 11)
    - European Community/Union, 1992-1993 (Box 269, Folder 12)
    - Foreign Relations, 1991-1994 (Box 269, Folder 13)
    - Freedom of Expression Institute, 1994-1995 (Box 269, Folder 14)
    - Fund for a Free South Africa (FreeSA), 1989 (Box 269, Folder 15)
    - Gay/Lesbian Rights, 1993-1994 (Box 269, Folder 16)
    - Gazankulu, 1990-1994 (Box 269, Folder 17)
    - Goldstone Commission
      - Press Clippings, 1992-1994 (Box 269, Folder 18)
      - Press Releases, 1993 March 16-17 (Box 269, Folder 19)
    - Grahamstown Rural Committee, 1989-1994 (Box 269, Folder 20)
    - Heritage Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 269, Folder 21)
    - Holdstock, T. Len, Education: Toward Heaven or Hell, 1987 (Box 269, Folder 22)
    - Homelands--General, 1990-1994; (4 Folders) (Box 269, Folder 23 to 26)
    - Hostels
      - Draft Report, 1991-1992 (Box 269, Folder 27)
      - Press Clippings, 1990-1994 (Box 269, Folder 28)
    - Human Rights Commission, 1989-1993 (Box 269, Folder 29)
    - Human Rights Commission
      - Area Repression Report, 1991-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Human Rights Review, 1990-1991 (Box 270, Folder 3)
      - Human Rights Update, 1991-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Monthly Report, 1994-1996; (3 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Monthly Repression Report, 1993 (Box 270, Folder 9)
      - Political Imprisonment in South Africa, 1991 April (Box 270, Folder 10)
    - Human Rights Committee
      - Human Rights Report, 1996 (Box 270, Folder 11)
      - Monthly Report, 1995 March (Box 270, Folder 12)
    - Human Sciences Research Council, 1992, 1994 (Box 270, Folder 13)
    - IDOC--African Files, 1993-1994 (Box 270, Folder 14)
    - Independent Board of Inquiry Into Informal Repression (IBIIR)
      - Memorandum, 1990 July (Box 271, Folder 1)
      - Reports, 1990-1994; (6 Folders) (Box 271, Folder 2 to 7)
    - Index on Censorship, 1990-1992 (Box 271, Folder 8)
    - Information Centre on South Africa, 1989-1990 (Box 271, Folder 9)
    - Inkatha, 1989-1990 (Box 271, Folder 10)
    - Institute for Mult-Party Democracy, 1993, 1995 (Box 271, Folder 11)
    - Institute for Public Interest Law and Research, 1991-1992 (Box 271, Folder 12)
    - International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), 1991 (Box 271, Folder 13)
    - International Mobilisation: Against Apartheid and for the Liberation of Southern Africa, 1990 (Box 271, Folder 14)
    - International Republican Institute--South Africa: Campaign And Election Report, 1994 April 26-29 (Box 271, Folder 15)
    - The Journal of the Human Rights Trust Monitor, 1989-1991, 1993, (2 Folders) (Box 271, Folder 16 to 17)
    - Justice
      - Access, 1989-1991 (Box 271, Folder 18)
      - Monitors, 1991 (Box 271, Folder 19)
      - Obstacles to Justice, 1989-1991 (Box 271, Folder 20)
    - KaNgwane, 1989-1993 (Box 271, Folder 21)
    - KwaNdebele, 1986, 1992-1994 (Box 271, Folder 22)
    - KwaZulu
      - Freedom of Expression, 1991-1994 (Box 271, Folder 23)
      - Inkatha--Links--United States, 1977-1994 (Box 272, Folder 1)
      - KwaZulu/Natal--Federalism, 1992-1994 (Box 272, Folder 2)
    - Language, 1992-1994 (Box 272, Folder 3)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1990-1994 (Box 272, Folder 4)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 272, Folder 5)
    - Lawyers for Human Rights
      - General, 1989-1990 (Box 272, Folder 6)
      - National Office, 1990-1991, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 7)
      - Publications, 1992 (Box 272, Folder 8)
      - Reports--Annual, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 272, Folder 9)
      - RIGHTS, 1990-1994; (2 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Lebowa, 1990-1994 (Box 272, Folder 12)
    - Legal Resources Centre, 1989-1992 (Box 272, Folder 13)
    - Local Government, 1990, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 14)
    - Mahomed, Ismail, 1991 (Box 272, Folder 15)
    - Mandela, Winnie, 1992-1994 (Box 272, Folder 16)
    - Media Institute of Southern Africa, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 17)
    - Medical Education for South African Blacks, Inc., 1992 (Box 272, Folder 18)
    - Medicine, 1990, 1992, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 19)
    - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 20)
    - National Party, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 21)
    - National Peace Accord, 1993 (Box 272, Folder 22)
    - National Peacekeeping Force, 1994 (Box 272, Folder 23)
    - Negotiations--Key Steps, 1992-1994 (Box 272, Folder 24)
    - Operation Hunger, 1992 (Box 273, Folder 1)
    - Organization of African Unity, 1992 (Box 273, Folder 2-3)
    - Pan Africanist Congress (PAC), 1991-1994 (Box 273, Folder 4)
    - Peace Action, 1992-1994 (Box 273, Folder 5)
    - Physicians for Human Rights, 1991 (Box 273, Folder 6)
    - Pietermaritzburg Agency (PACSA), 1989-1994 (Box 273, Folder 7)
    - Political Prisoners
      - Africa Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 273, Folder 8)
      - General Memos, 1990-1992 (Box 273, Folder 9)
      - Press Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 273, Folder 10)
    - Political Support, 1992-1994 (Box 273, Folder 11)
    - Project for the Study of Violence, 1991 (Box 273, Folder 12)
    - Publications Miscellaneous, 1989, 1991 (Box 273, Folder 13)
    - Right Wing, 1992-1994 (Box 273, Folder 14)
    - QwaQwa, 1991-1994 (Box 273, Folder 15)
    - Sanctions, 1991-1993 (Box 273, Folder 16)
    - Saspost, 1992 (Box 273, Folder 17)
    - South Africa Now (television program), 1988-1989 (Box 273, Folder 18)
    - South African Communist Party (SACP), 1991-1994 (Box 273, Folder 19)
    - South African Council of Churches (SACC)
      - APS News And Features Bulletin, 1982-1988 (Box 273, Folder 20)
      - Pamphlets, 1987-1989 (Box 273, Folder 21)
      - Position Papers/Documents, 1987-1994 (Box 273, Folder 22)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR)
      - Frontiers of Freedom, 1994-1995 (Box 273, Folder 23)
      - Statistics--Conflicts--Human Rights Commission, 1992-1993 (Box 273, Folder 24)
      - Watchdog on the South African Election, 1993-1994 (Box 273, Folder 25)
    - South African Union of Journalists, 1991 (Box 273, Folder 26)
    - Southern Africa Church News, 1991-1993 (Box 273, Folder 27)
    - Southern Africa Exclusive, 1993 (Box 273, Folder 28)
    - SouthScan: A Weekly Bulletin of Southern African Affairs, 1990-1994 (Box 273, Folder 29)
    - Streetwise: The Street Law Magazine, 1989, 1992 (Box 273, Folder 30)
    - TransAfrica, 1991 (Box 274, Folder 1)
    - Transfer of Land to the Self-Governing Territories, 1992-1993 (Box 274, Folder 2)
    - Transkei
      - Background Information, 1991-1993 (Box 274, Folder 3)
      - Background Information, 1991-1993 (Box 274, Folder 3a)
      - Press Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 274, Folder 4)
    - United Nations
      - General Assembly, 1988, 1990-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Press Clippings, 1992-1994 (Box 274, Folder 7)
      - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), 1988 (Box 274, Folder 8)
    - United States
      - South Africa Policy, 1989-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 9 to 10)
      - South Africa Relations, 1992-1993 (Box 274, Folder 11)
      - U.S. State Department Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 274, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1990 (Box 274, Folder 13)
    - Venda, 1989-1994 (Box 274, Folder 14)
    - Writers
      - Conference, 1991 November (Box 274, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence
        - Africa Watch, 1991 (Box 274, Folder 16)
        - General, 1991 (Box 274, Folder 17)
      - Human Rights Abuses, 1981-1993 (Box 274, Folder 18)
      - Papers, 1990 (Box 274, Folder 19)
    - Yunus Mahomed Case, 1989 (Box 274, Folder 20)
- Series 3: Other Country Files, 1985-1997
  In the early 1990s, HRW/Africa expanded its mission beyond its initial concentration on southern Africa and the Horn of Africa to include the entire continent. The files comprise the following states: Angola, Benin, Burundi, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, Congo, Djibouti, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Guinea, Ivory Coast, Kenya, Liberia, Malawi, Mali, Mauritania, Mozambique, Namibia, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Somalia, South Africa, Sudan, Togo, Uganda, West Africa, Zaire, Zambia, and Zimbabwe. The files contain archival materials collected or produced by Africa Watch staff, and are arranged alphabetically by country and subject. The files consist of articles, correspondence, memoranda, mission notes, newsletters, press clippings, publications, and general reports.
  - Africa--Press Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 275, Folder 1)
  - Angola
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 275, Folder 2)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 3)
  - Benin--Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 4)
  - Burundi
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996; (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 5 to 6)
    - FBIS Reports, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 7)
    - General, 1995-1996 (Box 275, Folder 8)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 9)
  - Cameroon--General, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 10)
  - Central African Republic (CAR)--Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 11)
  - Chad--Correspondence, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 12)
  - Congo--General, 1996 (Box 275, Folder 13)
  - Djibouti
    - FBIS Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 275, Folder 14)
    - Press Clippings, 1989-1994 (Box 275, Folder 15)
  - Eritrea
    - Afar Revolutionary Democratic Union, 1992-1993 (Box 275, Folder 16)
    - Eritrea Update, 1992-1994 (Box 275, Folder 17)
    - The Eritrean Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 275, Folder 18)
    - Press Clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 275, Folder 19)
    - Referendum Committee of Eritrea, 1993 (Box 275, Folder 20)
    - United Nations Policy, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 21)
  - Ethiopia
    - "A Derailing Transition: Freedom of Association and the Flight of Opposition Parties in Ethiopia", undated (Box 275, Folder 22)
    - Africa Watch (AFW)
    - Activities, 1988-1995 (Box 275, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990, 1992-1994 (Box 275, Folder 24)
    - Aklilu Tellila Wegi--Asylum Application, 1993 (Box 275, Folder 25)
    - All AMHARA People's Organization, 1992-1993 (Box 275, Folder 26)
    - Amnesty International, 1989-1995 (Box 275, Folder 27)
    - Background, 1992 (Box 275, Folder 28)
    - Coalition of Ethiopian Democratic Forces (COEDF), 1991-1992 (Box 275, Folder 29)
    - Constitution, undated (Box 275, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence
      - Contacts, 1991-1995 (Box 275, Folder 31)
      - Individual Letters and Testimony, 1993-1994 2070] (Box 275, Folder 32)
      - Official Documents, 1993 (Box 275, Folder 33)
      - Specific, 1989-1990 (Box 275, Folder 34)
    - Ethiopian League for Human Rights (ELHR), 1993 (Box 275, Folder 35)
    - Ethiopian Medhin Democratic Party (MEDHIN), 1993 (Box 275, Folder 36)
    - Famine, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 37)
    - FBIS Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 275, Folder 38)
    - Fund for Peace, 1991 (Box 275, Folder 39)
    - Government, 1993-1995 (Box 275, Folder 40)
    - Human Rights Council, 1992-1994 (Box 275, Folder 41)
    - International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), 1991 (Box 275, Folder 42)
    - Laws, 1972, 1975 (Box 275, Folder 43)
    - Leland, Mickey--Press Clippings, 1989 (Box 275, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1995 (Box 275, Folder 45)
    - Mission--Correspondence, 1995 (Box 276, Folder 1)
    - National Democratic Institute, 1994 (Box 276, Folder 2)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1994 (Box 276, Folder 3)
    - Opposition Parties, 1992-1993 (Box 276, Folder 4)
    - Organization of African Unity (OAU), 1988 (Box 276, Folder 5)
    - OROMO Liberation Front Central Committee, (2 Folders) (Box 276, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Political Conflict, 1993-1994 (Box 276, Folder 8)
    - Press Clippings, 1987-1993; (11 Folders) (Box 276, Folder 9 to 19)
    - Press Clippings, 1994-1996; (4 Folders) (Box 277, Folder 1 to 4)
    - The RAND Corporation Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 277, Folder 5)
    - Symposium on the Making of a New Ethiopian Constitution, 1993-1994 (Box 277, Folder 6)
    - The Third Round: An Ethiopian Clandestine Newsletter, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 7)
    - United Nations--Policy, 1991, 1993-1995 (Box 277, Folder 8)
    - United States
      - Administration/Executive--Policy, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 9)
      - Congress
        - Policy, 1989-1994 (Box 277, Folder 10)
        - Reports--Congressional Research Service (CRS), 1990, 1992 (Box 277, Folder 11)
        - Testimony, 1989-1990, 1992-1994 (Box 277, Folder 12)
      - Department of Justice--(INS), 1993, 1995 (Box 277, Folder 13)
      - Office of U.S. Foreign Disaster Assistance (OFDA), 1990-1991, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 14)
      - State Department--Policy, 1989-1991, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees (Box 277, Folder 16)
    - War Crimes Trial, 1994-1995 (Box 277, Folder 17)
  - Europe--General, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 18)
  - Guinea--General, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 19)
  - Ivory Coast--Correspondence, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 20)
  - Kenya--Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 277, Folder 21)
  - Liberia
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 277, Folder 22)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1993-1994 (Box 277, Folder 23)
    - Political Conflict/U.N. Issues, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 24)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 25)
    - Refugees, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 26)
  - Malawi
    - Agriculture/Industry, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 28)
    - Education Issues, undated (Box 277, Folder 29)
    - Political Issues, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 30)
    - Publications/Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 277, Folder 31)
  - Mali--General, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 32)
  - Mauritania
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 33)
    - Press Clippings, 1993, 1995 (Box 277, Folder 34)
  - Mozambique
    - Op Ed/ Commentary, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 35)
    - Political Issues, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 36)
    - Publications/Reports, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 37)
  - Namibia
    - General, 1994, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 38)
    - Sister Namibia, 1993-1996 (Box 277, Folder 39)
  - Nigeria
    - Civil Rights Issues, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 277, Folder 41)
    - Economy, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 42)
    - Political Issues, 1993 (Box 277, Folder 43)
    - Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 277, Folder 44)
    - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 277, Folder 45)
  - Rwanda
    - Correspondence, 1993-1996; (2 Folders) (Box 278, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Foreign Aid, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 3)
    - French/Rwanda Relations, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 4)
    - Guggenheim Foundation--Grant, 1996 (Box 278, Folder 5)
      [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2072]
    - Interviews, 1995 (Box 278, Folder 6)
    - Netherlands Organization for International Development Cooperation (NOVIB)--Grant, 1996 (Box 278, Folder 7)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 8)
    - Political Conflicts, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 9)
    - Press Clippings, 1994, 1996-1997 (Box 278, Folder 10)
    - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 11)
    - Refugees
      - Atrocities, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 12)
      - Camps, 1996 (Box 278, Folder 13)
    - Report--Budget, 1995 (Box 278, Folder 14)
    - United States-Rwanda Relations, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 15)
  - Senegal
    - Educational System, 1994 (Box 278, Folder 16)
    - Political Issues, 1993 (Box 278, Folder 17)
  - Sierra Leone--Press Clippings, 1996 (Box 278, Folder 18)
  - Somalia
    - Press Clippings, 1992-1993 March 31, (6 Folders) (Box 278, Folder 19 to 24)
    - Press Clippings, 1993 April 1-1993 December 31; (9 Folders) (Box 279, Folder 1 to 9)
    - Press Clippings, 1993-1996; (9 Folders) (Box 280, Folder 1 to 9)
    - African Lawyers Committee for Human Rights (ALC), 1993 (Box 280, Folder 10)
    - Africa Watch
      - Activities, 1993 (Box 280, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1990, 1992-1993, (5 Folders) (Box 280, Folder 12 to 16)
      - Memorandum
        - General, 1993-1995 (Box 280, Folder 17)
        - Internal, 1992 2068] (Box 280, Folder 18)
      - Notes--Mendez, Juan E., 1993 (Box 280, Folder 19)
      - Reports, 1993 (Box 280, Folder 20)
      - Testimony, 1990, 1992-1993 (Box 280, Folder 21)
    - Aid Groups, 1989-1993 (Box 281, Folder 1)
    - Amnesty International, 1985-1990; (2 Folders) (Box 281, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Articles, 1992-1994 (Box 281, Folder 4)
    - Bread for the World, 1991 (Box 281, Folder 5)
    - Chemical Weapons, 1988-1989 (Box 281, Folder 6)
    - Concerned Somalis, 1991, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 7)
    - Congressional Research Service (CRS) Reports, 1990 1992-1993- (Box 281, Folder 8)
    - Contacts, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 281, Folder 10)
    - European Association of Somali Studies, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 11)
    - Foreign Aid, 1994 (Box 281, Folder 12)
    - Human Rights Groups (Box 281, Folder 13)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) Country Profile, 1989-1990, 1993 (Box 281, Folder 14)